# MAXIM WITTEK

Software Developer.

#### **CONTACT INFO**

maxwittek+resume@gmail.com Seattle, WA

#### ONLINE

github.com/wittekm LinkedIn

### **SKILLS**

Java Python

Typescript w/ React

C++

Ruby w/ Rails Relational, nonrelational and graph DBs

As this list grows, it's easiest to say that I pick up new technologies and practices pretty easily.

## **Profile**

Full-stack software engineer with 7+ years experience in building <u>distributed services</u>, <u>native libraries</u>, and <u>frontend experiences</u>. I'm happiest when developing or maintaining a well-tested, reasonable codebase, in an engaging and ethical position (so, an immediate 'no thank you' to adtech or fintech).

# **Experience**

### Dropbox (2015-Current)

Software Engineer 3 (Feb 2018-Current)

<u>Tech lead</u> on our Slack integration, Gmail addon and SCIM (Active Directory) integration. Individual contributor, task management, and some limited people management. Frequently worked together with external business partners and engineers at Slack, Microsoft and Google, respectively.

Software Engineer 2 & 3 (June 2015-Feb 2018)

Developer on the Cash team, responsible for worldwide payments processing, product catalog, ETLs, revenue reporting, and compliance.

### Amazon.com (2012-2015)

Software Development Engineer II (April 2014 - December 2014)

On loan to an NDA'd project, working on a cross-platform layout & rendering engine in C++03.

Tech: worked with Boost libraries, OpenGL ES, Android NDK and Cocoa.

Software Development Engineer I & II

(August 2012 - April 2014, December 2014 - June 2015)

Member of the Kindle Content Inspection & Automation team, developing technology to ensure that only quality books are made available on the Kindle Store, and that publishers have the rights to the content. Tech: Java services, SpringMVC sites, Ruby on Rails sites, distributed computing via Amazon SWF/SNS/SQS, SQL & NoSQL (DynamoDB). Common patterns: Event Sourcing, Event Bus / ESB.

## Internships

Amazon.com (2011)

Crestron Electronics (2009)

BlackRock Solutions (2008)

# **Education**

# University of Michigan (2008 to 2012)

Bachelors of Science in Engineering, Computer Science

Relevant classes included UI Development, Intro to Artificial Intelligence, Advanced Programming and Design Patterns, Operating Systems, Computer Organization/Architecture, Data Structures & Algorithms, Natural Language Processing.

Jun 2019

2 of 2